# **George Chen**

**Junior Software Developer** 

Brooklyn, NY 11228 (917) 889-1891 georgechen1338@gmail.com

georgechen1338@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/georgechen1338/ https://georgechen.netlify.app/

#### **PROJECTS**

https://github.com/verybamboo/whackadiglett (03/22) — Front-end game made with JavaScript, HTML and CSS. Custom take on Whack-a-mole.

https://backrub.wiki/ (04/22) — 3 person group project, created a website that was an API of tech articles from the NYT for the last 20 years. Front-end made with React and back-end made with MongoDB and hosted on Heroku.

https://haterip.netlify.app/ (05/22) — Group project where we made a clone of Twitter using React as the front-end and Django, MySQL for a deployed back-end.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**General Assembly,** New York, NY Software Engineering Immersive Fellow February 2022 - May 2022

- Completed industry-leading Software Engineering Immersive program focusing on 480+ hours of full-stack web development.
- Created 4 web apps in various coding languages and frameworks, such as HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React and Python.
- Deployed databases and data structures using MongoDB, Heroku, Django, Flask, PostgreSQL and MySQL.
- Learned to work both as a solo developer and in a group environment with fellow cohort members.

Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center - RARC, New York, NY Animal Research Technician
March 2019 - March 2020

- Provided routine care of research animals.
- Administered medications (pills, injections) as instructed.
- Maintained records in an organized and up-to-date manner.
- Assisted in ensuring compliance with regulatory requirements related to care of laboratory animals.
- Communicated data to all NYULMC staff as needed.

### SKILLS

Coding Languages
HTML/CSS
JavaScript (Node.js, React)
Python

<u>Frameworks</u> Django Express.js Flask

<u>Database Management</u> Heroku PostgreSQL MySQL

## **LANGUAGES**

Cantonese - Fluent

Mandarin - Conversational

English - Fluent

# **EDUCATION**

**General Assembly,** New York, NY Software Engineering Immersive February 2022 - May 2022

**CUNY Hunter College,** New York, NY *Bachelor of Arts, Psychology* September 2013 - June 2016